Guide to the John Caughlan Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- John Caughlan papers, 1936-1999; 1950-1989; 0704-002; 32.39 cubic feet 32 boxes, two oversize folders and two vertical files
  - Personal and Professional Papers, 1936-1999
    - Subject Files
      - Elections, 1996
        - Independent Progressive Political Organizing Committee, 1996 (Box-folder 23/5)
        - Miscellaneous, 1996 (Box-folder 23/6)
      - Fort Lewis Riot and Court Martial, 1944, 1987 (Box-folder 23/7)
      - Initiative 325 (Anti-Nuclear), 1978-1979 (Box-folder 23/8)
      - Isserman, Abraham, 1950, 1977 (Box-folder 23/9)
      - Jackson, Jesse, 1984 (Box-folder 23/10)
      - Law, Laura, 1940, 1948-1950, 1980, 1987, 1992, 1999 (Box-folder 23/11)
        Contains clippings, correspondence and ephemera
      - Lawyers Committee for International Human Rights (Asylum), 1979, undated (Box-folder 23/12)
      - Loyalty Oaths, 1947-1949, undated (Box-folder 23/13-14)
      - Mark Curtis Defense Committee, 1990, undated (Box-folder 23/15)
      - Maritime Unions and the Magnuson Act, 1952 (Box-folder 23/16)
      - McCarran Act (Internal Security Act of 1950) Analyses and Pleadings, 1950, undated (Box-folder 23/17-21)
      - O'Higgins, Pablo, 1975-1987, undated (Box-folder 23/22-23)
      - Palestine Project, 1984-1987, undated (Box-folder 23/24)
      - Peace in Vietnam - Municipal Initiative, 1967, undated (Box-folder 23/25)
        Possibly drafted by Caughlan
      - Philippines
        Caughlan's folder titles have been retained where they are known. Most folders contain a mix of newsletters, fact sheets, ephemera and clippings.
        - Anti-Martial Law Coalition (later the Coalition Against the Marcos Dictatorship), 1977, 1981, undated (Box-folder 23/26)
        - Asia Resource Center, 1982, 1987, undated (Box-folder 23/27)
        - Clippings, 1977 (Box-folder 23/28)
        - Conference and Convention Files: Manila Conference on the Law of the World, 1977 (Box-folder 23/29-30)
        - Ephemera, 1976-1977, undated (Box-folder 23/31)
        - Free Filipinos Legal Assistance Group, 1981-1998, undated (Box-folder 23/32)
        - Friends of the Filipino People, 1977, undated (Box-folder 23/33)
        - Information Regarding Detainees, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/1-4)
        - Information Regarding Torture, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/5)
        - Letters from Bicutan Detainees, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/6)
        - Luce, Don and Clergy and Laity Concerned, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/7)
        - Miscellaneous Background Material, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/8-9)
        - Miscellany, 1974-1977, undated (Box-folder 24/10-12)
        - National Committee to Oppose the Marcos State Visit; Committee to Oppose the Marcos Visit (Seattle, Washington), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 24/13)
        - National Democratic Front (Philippines), 1985-1986 (Box-folder 24/14)
        - Publications, 1975-1986, undated (Box-folder 24/15-17)
        - World Peace Through Law Investigating Committee, 1977, undated (Box-folder 24/18)
      - Seattle Liberation Front, 1970, undated (Box-folder 24/19)
      - Shibley, George (Civilian lawyer arrested by military police), 1956, undated (Box-folder 24/20)
      - United States Congress, House Committee on Un-American Affairs (HUAC), 1948, 1959-1961, undated (Box-folder 24/21-22)
        Includes correspondence with Frank J. Donner.
      - Vietnam War, 1957, 1968-1970, undated (Box-folder 24/23-29)
        Includes pamphlets, newsletters and sample pleadings relating to conscientious objector and Selective Service cases as well as nonpayment of war taxes and background information on the war.
      - Washington Pension Union, 1987 (Box-folder 24/30)
      - Washington State Rainbow Coalition, 1989-1992, undated (Box-folder 24/31)
      - Wolf, Hazel, 1979, 1988, 1991-1996, undated (Box-folder 25/1)
        Inclues clippings, writings, correspondence and transcripts. Transcripts are of interviews with Caughlan regarding Hazel Wolf, her activism and her immigration case, conducted by Susan Starbuck for a biography of Wolf. These transcripts also contain a fair amount of material about Caughlan's own activism.
      - Woodson, Susan and Woodson, Harold Jr., 1961, 1998 (Box-folder 25/2)
    - Course Materials
      - Civil Rights Seminar, Edmonds Community College, 1973 (Box-folder 25/3-5)
      - The Cold War - Lifetime Learning Center (course description only), 1999 (Box-folder 25/6)
    - Case Files of Others, 1930s-1970s, undated (Box-folder 25/7-26/17)
      Primarily pleadings; some have Caughlan's markings or notes. Topics include Cuba, race discrimination, immigration, free speech, right to counsel, treason (Julius and Ethel Rosenberg, Morton Sobell), the Smith Act, Alger Hiss (coram nobis petition), "subversive activities," the Communist Party of the United States. The largest amount of material in this series relates to cases of the American Committe to Protect the Foreign-Born.
    - Publications, 1961, 1968 (Box-folder 26/18-19)
      Caughlan's copies of the New Testament and the Selected Military Writings of Mao Tse-Tung
    - Certificates, 1936, 1947, 1956 (Box-folder Miscellaneous Oversize Box 3)
    - Obituaries, Memorials and Tributes to Others, 1963-1972, 1985-1997 (Box-folder 26/20)
    - Ephemera, 1952, 1963-1964, 1985, 1993, undated (Box-folder 26/21-24)
    - Clippings
      - About Caughlan and his Cases, 1940, 1954, 1964, 1987, undated (Box-folder 27/1)
      - "[Political] Climate, New York Times", 1952-1953, undated (Box-folder 27/2-3)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950s-1980s (Box-folder 27/4)
    - Legal Documents, 1954 (Box-folder 27/5)
  - Related Organizations' Records, 1950-1998
    - American Civil Liberties Union of Washington, Board of Directors, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 27/6)
      Primarily meeting agendas and minutes.
    - Committee for Justice for Orozco and Carcamo, 1992-1994, undated (Box-folder 27/7)
      The Committee was founded to defend Oscar Uceda-Carcamo and Miguel Orozco-Delgado two refugees who worked for refugee assistance organizations and who were indicted for conspiracy and filing false documents. Uceda-Carcamo is from El Salvador while Orozco-Delgado is from Mexico. The defense was ultimately successful. Orozco-Delgado was married to Caughlan's daughter, Mary.
    - Florence Bean James Memorial Committee, 1988, undated (Box-folder 27/8-9)
      Primarily correspondence, ephemera, notes, clippings, and drafts of the script for a multimedia presentation at the memorial.
    - Line of March
      - Incoming Letters, 1988-1989, undated (Box-folder 27/10)
      - Outgoing Letters, 1983, 1988-1989, undated (Box-folder 27/11)
      - Memoranda, 1988-1989, undated (Box-folder 27/12-13)
      - Speeches and Writings, undated (Box-folder 27/14-22)
        Includes writings by Caughlan as well as writings by others, unidentified pieces and pieces written jointly by Line of March participants.
      - Reports, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 27/23)
      - Minutes and Agenda, 1989, undated (Box-folder 27/24)
      - Legal Documents, 1986 (Box-folder 27/25)
      - National Board Report, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 27/26-28)
      - Pleadings, 1989, undated (Box-folder 27/29)
      - Notebook 1, undated (Box-folder 27/30-32)
      - Notebook 2, undated (Box-folder 28/1-4)
      - Subject File: Frontline, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 28/5-7)
      - Publications
        - Line of March Internal Bulletin, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 28/8-9)
        - Frontline, 1982 (Box-folder 28/10)
        - Notes, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 28/11)
        - The Restoration of Capitalism in the Soviet Union, undated (Box-folder 12/12-13)
        - Miscellany, 1980-1988, undated (Box-folder 28/14-16)
      - Notes, undated (Box-folder 28/17)
      - Clippings, 1984, 1988, undated (Box-folder 28/18)
      - Ephemera, 1988, undated (Box-folder 28/19)
      - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 28/20)
    - National Lawyers Guild
      - National Organization
        - Historical Features, 1968, 1986-1998, undated (Box-folder 28/21)
        - General Correspondence, 1957-1960, 1977-1984 (Box-folder 28/22)
        - Pleadings and Petitions, 1958,1965, 1998, undated (Box-folder 28/23-24)
        - National Executive Board and National Executive Committee, 1960s-1980s (Box-folder 28/25-29/1)
          Primarily correspondence, agendas and minutes.
        - Committees and Topical Divisions
          - Affirmative Action/Anti-Discrimination Committee, 1981 (Box-folder 29/2)
          - Civil Liberties Committee, 1985 (Box-folder 29/3)
          - Committee on Native American Struggles, 1983-1985, undated (Box-folder 29/4-6)
            Material primarily concerns the rights of the Miskito tribe of Nicaragua (some are in Spanish); some materials relating to North American tribes and issues are also present.
          - International Committee, 1977-1986, 1994, undated
            Caughlan served as chair of the International Committee.
            - Central America Task Force
              - Administrative Records, 1981-1986, undated (Box-folder 29/7-8)
                Primarily correspondence, memos and newsletters.
              - Citizens Tribunal on United States Government Involvement in Central American and the Caribbean (Seattle), Planning Materials and Transcript, 1984-1987, undated (Box-folder 29/9-11)
              - 1983 Delegation (Box-folder 29/12-14)
                Caughlan visited Nicaragua in 1983 as part of a delegation invited by the Asociacion de Juristas Democraticos de Nicaragua (Democratic Jurists Association of Nicaragua), representatives of whom had previously visited Seattle. The delegation included members of the National Lawyers Guild, the Lawyers Committee Against Intervention in Central America (with which Caughlan seems to have also been affiliated) and the National Conference of Black Lawyers.
                Includes notes, correspondence, extensive background material prepared for the participants, and writings by Caughlan on the subject of the delegation and the Nicaraguan jurists' visit. A small amount of the material is in Spanish.
              - 1984 Delegation, 1981-1989, undated (Box-folder 29/15-30/1)
                The purpose of this delegation was to observe and report on the Nicaraguan elections. Includes Caughlan's travel diary, background material prepared for participants, and the delgation's final report.
            - Peace and Disarmament Subcommittee, 1979-1986, undated (Box-folder 30/2-4)
              Includes a speech by Ann Fagan Ginger delivered at a Peace and Disarmament Subcommittee workshop and a letter by Caughlan in response, as well as drafts of other writings by Caughlan.
            - Philippines Delegation, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 30/5)
            - Miscellaneous, 1977-1984, undated (Box-folder 30/6)
              Includes writings, a speech by Caughlan, and material on the Philippines.
          - Labor Committee, 1984 (Box-folder 30/7)
          - Marxism and the Law Subcommittee, 1993 (Box-folder 30/8)
          - Mississippi Summer Project, 1964 (Box-folder 30/9-10)
          - National Immigration Project, 1978-1986, undated (Box-folder 30/11-17)
          - National Prison Project, 1978-1979, undated (Box-folder 30/18)
          - Regional Vice Presidents and Regional Vice President Support Committee, 1985-1986, undated (Box-folder 30/19-21)
        - Subject Files
          - Guild 50th Anniversary, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 30/22)
            Includes planning materials, clippings and commemorative journal.
          - Guild Lawsuits against United States Attorney General and Federal Bureau of Investigation, 1955, 1983-1984, undated (Box-folder 30/23)
          - International Longshoremen's and Warehousemen's Union, 1980 (Box-folder 30/24)
            Includes a letter from Harry Bridges
          - Japanese Visitors, 1992 (Box-folder 30/25)
            Includes copies of Dateline Tokyo newsletter
          - Martin, Gordon, 1950, 1957 (Box-folder 30/26)
          - Racism, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 30/27)
          - Selective Service and Draft Issues, 1963, 1966-1968, undated (Box-folder 30/28-29)
        - Conference and Convention Files: Guild Annual Conventions, 1964-1998
          - Annual Conventions, 1964-1998 (Box-folder 30/30-31/14)
            The 1997 Convention materials include a piece (a reflection on the Convention and the Guild's history) by Caughlan entitled "La Lucha Continua."
          - Northwest Regional Conference, 1985, undated (Box-folder 31/15-17)
        - Plaque, 1997 (Box-folder 31/18)
          Presented to Caughlan at the Guild's 1997 Annual Convention, in honor of his sixty years of membership.
        - Writings, 1953, 1967, 1981, undated (Box-folder 31/19-25)
          The first folder contains a piece on the McCarran Act that may or may not be by Caughlan.
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 31/26)
        - Contract between Guild and Guild National Staff Union, 1984 (Box-folder 31/27)
      - National Lawyers Guild, Seattle Chapter
        - Historical Features, undated (Box-folder 31/28)
        - General Correspondence, 1971-1998 (Box-folder 31/29)
        - Minutes and Staff Reports, 1979-1986 (Box-folder 31/30)
        - Financial Records, 1986, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 31/31)
        - Policy Board, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 32/1)
        - Executive Board, 1981-1988 (Box-folder 32/2)
        - Nuclear Affairs Committee, 1979-1985, undated (Box-folder 32/3-8)
          This committee seems to have operated at some point under the name Anti-Nuclear Committee, but it has not been possible to pinpoint the dates for each name.
          Includes some materials related to the defense of the Crabshell Alliance, the Washington State Public Power Supply System, Initiative 382, the State Energy Financing Accountability Act proposed for the 1980 election, and an act, also proposed for 1980, banning the importation of nuclear waste into Washington state and requiring voter approval of the construction of nuclear facilities.
        - Central America-Nicaragua Demonstration, undated (Box-folder 32/9)
        - Annual Banquet Journals, 1984-1987, 1990 (Box-folder 32/10)
        - Photo Album from 50th Anniversary Banquet, 1987 (Box-folder 32/11)
          Includes two snapshots of Caughlan at the banquet; and enlarged color photocopies of both.
        - Ephemera, 1968-1980, undated (Box-folder 32/12)
        - Notes, undated (Box-folder 32/13)
      - Other Chapters, 1969-1986, undated (Box-folder 32/14)
        Includes small amounts of material from chapters including Detroit, San Francisco, Portland (Oregon), New York City and Massachusetts.
    - Peace and Freedom Party of Washington State, 1965-1967, undated (Box-folder 32/15)
    - Paul Robeson Centennial Committee, 1969, 1998, undated (Box-folder 32/16-17)
      Contains a photograph of Paul Robeson at Peace Arch Park.
    - Seattle Lawyers' Selective Service Panel, 1968-1969, undated (Box-folder 32/18-19)
- John Caughlan papers and photographs, 1936-2003; 0704-003; 2.51 cubic feet 3 boxes
  Prison letters from Caughlan's eight months of incarceration in McNeil Island federal penitentiary in 1961 for failing to file tax returns in 1956 and 1957. Photographs from several civil rights and civil liberties cases of clients Caughlan represented, including the 1948 Canwell hearings on alleged un-American activity at the Univesity of Washington where Caughlan represented Professor Herbert Phillips, who refused to testify. Three UW professors, including Phillips, were later fired. Other photos depict Caughlan with members of the United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing, and Allied Workers of America (UCAPAWA), who were members of the John Caughlan Defense Committee, formed to support Caughlan after he was indicted by a federal grand jury for committing perjury after serving three years on the state Social Security Committee. The jury allege that Caughlan had lied about his communist beliefs at a government proceeding in 1946. He was later acquitted.
  No restrictions on access.
  Goldie Caughlan and Mary Orozco
  - BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS, 1942-1998; SERIES I (Box-folder 1/1-1/6)
    - Caughlan's Biographical Short Stories, c. 1998 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, October 3, 1994 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Book Reviews, 1993-1997 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Destroyed File List (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Caughlan's Campaign Brochure, 1942 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Lifetime Learning Center class on The Cold War, 1998 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - SUBJECT FILES ON COMMUNISM AND MCCARTHYISM, 1937-2012; SERIES II (Box-folder 1/7-1/26)
    - Involving Caughlan, 1937-2012; Subseries A (Box-folder 1/7-1/11)
      - Draft Article on Cuba, 1994 (Box-folder 1/7)
      - Nicolai Redin notes with newspaper clipping, 1946 (Box-folder 1/8)
      - Seattle Repertory Playhouse, 1937-2012 (Box-folder 1/9)
      - Caughlan Accused of Communism and Mocking Justice System, 1948-1970 (Box-folder 1/10)
      - Miscellaneous Commentary and Letters on Communism, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Documents & Writings By Others, 1949-2001; Subseries B (Box-folder 1/12-1/26)
      - Communist conviction trial, newspaper clipping, Undated (Box-folder 1/12)
      - Seattle Smith Act Case- Washington State Executive Board (CP), Undated (Box-folder 1/13)
      - Lenus Westman Memorial Flyer, January 22, 1995 (Box-folder 1/14)
      - Red Scare of 1954 at Reed College, March 1992-1997 (Box-folder 1/15)
      - Washington State Oral History publication: Charles Hodde, 1997 (Box-folder 1/16)
      - Washington State Oral History publication: Albert Canwell, 1997 (Box-folder 1/17)
      - Letters and Newspaper Clippings on the Red Scare in Seattle, September 1952-Dec-98 (Box-folder 1/18)
      - Investigation of Communist Activities in the Pacific Northwest, October 3, 1952-June 2, 1955 (Box-folder 1/19)
      - Editorial on Communist Arrests, September 18, 1952 (Box-folder 1/20)
      - Newsletter on Senator Dulles, October 24, 1949 (Box-folder 1/21)
      - International Workers Order Certificate, 1949 (Box-folder 1/22)
      - Subversive Activities Control Act, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 1/23)
      - Mary Wheeler's Death, November 1992 (Box-folder 1/24)
      - Newspaper Article on McCarthyism, November 2001 (Box-folder 1/25)
      - Hazel Wolf on the McCarthy Period, May 24, 1990 (Box-folder 1/26)
  - LEGAL CASES, 1942-1979; SERIES III (Box-folder 2/1-2/16)
    - Caughlan As Attorney: Communist/Smith Act Trials, 1953-1972; Subseries A (Box-folder 2/1-2/2)
      - Daschbach v. United States, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - United States v. Robel, October 1966-1972 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Caughlan As Attorney: Labor Union/Immigration Trials, 1952-1957; Subseries B (Box-folder 2/3-2/6)
      - Supreme Court Briefs: Arnold v. National Union of Marine Cooks and Stewards, 1952 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - Supreme Court Petition for Rehearing: Rabang v. Boyd, May 1957 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - Supreme Court Brief: International Longshoremens' and Warehousemens' Union, Local 37 v. Boyd, May 1953 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - Supreme Court Petition for Rehearing: Wolf v. Boyd, with Caughlan's anecdote on Wolf, October 1956 (Box-folder 2/6)
    - Caughlan As Attorney: General Cases, 1947-1968; Subseries C (Box-folder 2/7-2/8)
      - State ex rel. Pennock v. Reeves briefs, 1947 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - Supreme Court Petitions: Collins v. State of Washington, October 1968 (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Court Cases and Legal Publications, 1942-1979; Subseries D (Box-folder 2/9-2/16)
      - Supreme Court Briefs: Gray v. Goodson, C. 1960 (Box-folder 2/9)
      - Briefs of the defendants of United States v. Foster, 1948 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - Court of Appeals Brief: Lenske v. United States, August 28, 1967 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - District Court Brief: United States v. Dennis, 1947 (Box-folder 2/12)
      - Book of Hearings on Foreign Affairs, May 02, 1979-August 02, 1979 (Box-folder 2/13)
      - United States v. Caughlan, 1963 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - Schneiderman v. United States pamphlet, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2/15)
      - The Mental Element in Crime: Lectures from the Hebrew University of Jerusalem, 1965 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - SUBJECT FILES: LABOR AND CIVIL RIGHTS, 1936-2003; SERIES IV (Box-folder 2/17-2/38)
    - Caughlan's Writings and Related Materials, 1936-1990; Subseries A (Box-folder 2/17-2/24)
      - Michael Withey-John Caughlan Domingo v. Philippines, cassette tape, Undated (Box-folder 2/17)
      - Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes film/teach-in, cassette tape and flyer, August 6, 1982-August 7, 1982 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - Carlos Bulosan and Local 37 Immigration, Undated (Box-folder 2/19)
      - Nicaraguan Elections, 1990 (Box-folder 2/20)
      - Writings on Political Reform, Undated (Box-folder 2/21)
      - Political Campaign Buttons, 1936-1985 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - The Rainbow Coalition and the Washington Commonwealth Federation, c. 1980s (Box-folder 2/23)
      - Civil Rights and Immigration, c. 1970s (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Articles and Publications, 1939-1999; Subseries B (Box-folder 2/25-2/29)
      - National Lawyers Guild, 1973-1997 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - Fort Lawton article copies, 1944-1998 (Box-folder 2/26)
      - National Guard Reservists, October 16, 1968 (Box-folder 2/27)
      - A Works Progress Administration (WPA) Survey of Power in Washington, February 1, 1939 (Box-folder 2/28)
      - Dick Law/Laura Law's Murder, 1940-1999 (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Other Activists, 1952-2003; Subseries C (Box-folder 2/30-2/38)
      - Funding Proposals to the Committee for Justice for Orozco and Carcamo, May 3, 1994-October 12, 1994 (Box-folder 2/30)
      - Newsletters from the Committee for Justice for Domingo and Viernes, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 2/31)
      - Flyer from the Sisters of Bat Shalom, May 3, 1998 (Box-folder 2/32)
      - Brochure and Commentary on Unions, C. 1998 (Box-folder 2/33)
      - A Week in Mississippi, Newsletter by Mrs. Fawcett, April 10, 1965-April 17, 1965 (Box-folder 2/34)
      - Selma Waldman and Jewish Activism, 1964-2003 (Box-folder 2/35)
      - Committee for the Protection of the Foreign Born, Undated (Box-folder 2/36)
      - Paul Robeson, Part 1 of 2, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 2/37)
      - Paul Robeson, Part 2 of 2, 1952-1958 (Box-folder 2/38)
  - LETTERS, 1948-1999; SERIES V (Box-folder 3/1-3/11)
    - Organizational, 1954-1994; Subseries A (Box-folder 3/1-3/3)
      - William J. Pennock Memorial Association membership, 1954 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - Oregon Historical Society, March 2, 1994 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), November 28, 1994 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Personal, 1948-1999; Subseries B (Box-folder 3/4-3/9)
      - To and from Michael Royce, March 6, 1993-June 04, 1993 (Box-folder 3/4)
      - To Cynthia Anderson-Barker, January 10, 1994 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - To Carl Marzani, December 8, 1994 (Box-folder 3/6)
      - To Susan Gilmore, September 18, 1998 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Miscellaneous Cards and Correspondence, October 27, 1948-January 27, 1999 (Box-folder 3/8)
      - To Mrs. Caughlan from McNeil Island Corrections Center, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Concerning Communism, 1948-1997; Subseries C (Box-folder 3/10-3/11)
      - To and from Mark Jenkins, June 6, 1994-June 10, 1994 (Box-folder 3/10)
      - Letters Concerning Harvey Manning and Communism, October 11, 1948-September 11, 1997 (Box-folder 3/11)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS, 1936-1960s; SERIES VI (Box-folder 3/12-3/23)
    - Photograph of man standing outside of building, Undated (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Nicolai Redin photograph with newspaper clipping, July 16, 1946 (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Caughlan's Perjury Trial, 1948 (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Canwell Hearings: Ted Astley, July 1948 (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Communists and American Legion, May 2, 1936 (Box-folder 3/16)